<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fixeds on</title><link>https://nazareno.github.io/fixed/</link><description>Recent content in Fixeds on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://nazareno.github.io/fixed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Research</title><link>https://nazareno.github.io/research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nazareno.github.io/research/</guid><description>I strive to cultivate three characteristics in research: kindness, aversion for Discipline boundaries (interdisciplinary work is best), and curiosity for methods from different fields.
Below there is a list of selected publications with links. There is a more complete list on google scholar.
Data Visualization Can Anthropographics Promote Prosociality? A Review and Large-Sample Study ACM CHI 2021 Luiz Morais, Yvonne Jansen, Nazareno Andrade, Pierre Dragicevic open science site</description></item><item><title>Lab Projects</title><link>https://nazareno.github.io/lab-projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nazareno.github.io/lab-projects/</guid><description>I coordinate since 2012 the Lab Analytics, a Civic Data Science group I co-founded at UFCG. The lab usually has 20-30 researchers and software engineers and developed projects funded by Hewlett Packard, government agencies, startups, and NGOs. Some recent projects:
Parlametria [site][code][reports]
Platform to detect and predict activity patterns in law bills and congressmen work. It&amp;rsquo;s in use since 2019 by 80+ NGOs that monitor the Brazilian Congress.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://nazareno.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nazareno.github.io/about/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a Professor at Universidade Federal de Campina Grande (UFCG), in Brazil. I&amp;rsquo;m in the Computer Science Department, where I:
Teach Data Science, Data Visualization, Software Development, and Research Methods to Computer Science grad and undergrad students. I&amp;rsquo;ve also taught Art &amp;amp; Technology and Data Visualization to journalists, artists, and architects.
Research Data Visualization, Music Information Retrieval, Data Science, Civic Tech, Machine Learning, and Social Computing. I maintain a list of publications.</description></item><item><title>Music Visualizations</title><link>https://nazareno.github.io/music-visualizations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nazareno.github.io/music-visualizations/</guid><description>This is a somewhat random but fun list of visualizations I&amp;rsquo;ve developed for various projects.
Energy and Valence in famous tropicalistas according to Spotify data, or Why is Maria Bethânia so intense?
Artists who influenced or where influenced by John Cage, from AllMusic data
How Miles Davis transitioned between collaborators from different groups in a latent space of jazz musicians.
The network of similar artists around Dominguinhos crawled from the Spotify API</description></item></channel></rss>